Contact

San Diego, CA 92122 949-466-2546 AliSarkeshik@gmail.com

Education

UCSD Certificate, Full Stack Web Development February 2019 to August 2019

UC Riverside Bachelor of Science, Chemistry

<u>LinkedIn</u>

www.linkedin.com/in/alisarkeshik

Technical Skills

JavaScript jQuery HTML Node.js React.js

MySQL

Publications

https://urlzs.com/Su7nh

Ali Sarkeshik

Summary

Solutions-driven Full Stack Developer/Software Engineer who uses ingenuity and creativity to build fluid and functional web applications. My previous experience includes method development in Chemistry and Instrumentation (hardware and software troubleshooting) in a resale and OEM environment.

Experience

UC San Diego Extension Full Stack Developer February 2019 - Present

GitHub: https://github.com/AliSarkeshik

Projects: https://alisarkeshik.github.io/UpdatedPortfolio/portfolio.html

- ➤ NBA Clicky Game (React.js): The user has 20 player cards to choose from. Clicking on a card adds 1 point to their total score. If the same card is clicked twice the game ends.
- ➤ JavaScript Trivia Game: The user has 3 minutes to answer all the questions. At the end their score is computed and printed to the screen.
- ➤ GifTastic (using AJAX): Clicking a button will display a GIF onto the screen. The user can then play and pause the GIFs when clicking on the GIF. Customize your GIFs by typing your request into the text field and clicking "Submit."
- Amazon Manager: MySQL, Node.js, Inquirer, and Express are utilized in this app which allows a Manager to view their inventory, see which items are running low, and add items.
- > Train Scheduler: Using Firebase, this "Train Scheduler" allows the user to input train information which is subsequently uploaded to a table at the top of the screen.

Group Projects

- > Travel Guide: This group project combines Javascript, AJAX, and APIs. The user enters their destination city and from there the app outputs Hotel information, points of interest, fun events, and weather.
- ➤ **Pub Crawl**: Our group project will help you match with a brewery that you probably have never heard of, but you will definitely love.

Technologies Used: Bootstrap, Express, JS/JQuery, Heroku, Node, and Handlebars.

Certificate program learning front-end and back-end technologies through a dynamic curriculum: Database Theory, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, MongoDB, MySQL, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Bookshelf.js, AJAX, Firebase, Command Line, Heroku, and Git.

PerkinElmer, Inc. Customer Support Engineer June 2018 - December 2018 San Diego, CA

- Provided on-site personalized support services for PerkinElmerinstruments
- Provided troubleshooting expertise and repair skills needed to help identify and resolve issues related to hardware, software or applications support.
- Performed PMs, installs, and repairs on various Perkin Elmer instruments (Janus, LabChip, SciClone, Zephyr, and Euroimmune products).

Roche Diagnostics Planned Activities Specialist/Field Service Engineer January 2018 - May 2018 Greater San Diego Area (Contract position via Tailored Management)

- Performed on-site preventative maintenance, installation, and technical updates (TSB's) on company products (Cobas 6000 and 8000 analyzers).
- Diagnosed mechanical, hardware, software and system failures.
- Trained in: CD Foundations of Hardware, IT Products, c6000/8000 Service Operator Training, and Cobas 6000 Install/Core Service.

BioSurplus, Inc. Service Engineer January 2017 - July 2017 San Diego, CA

- Determined the re-sale viability of company acquisitions.
- Diagnosed, repaired, and serviced a wide range of laboratory equipment.
- Systems included but were not limited to: Flow Cytometry, Centrifuges, Refrigeration Systems, Automated Liquid Handlers, and HPLC.

Versum Materials (Formerly known as Air Products and Chemicals, Inc.) Analytical Chemist November 2013 - January 2017 Carlsbad, CA (Contract Position via The Fountain Group: Nov 2013 – May 2015)

- Worked closely with a team of researchers to support method development for new semi-conductor products.
- Performed hands on installation (hardware/software), calibrations, troubleshooting, and maintenance on GC instruments (Agilent 5973/6850/6890/Thermo Trace 1310).
- GC-TCD/GC-FID, GC-MS, DIP-MS analysis of organo silanes and GC-PHID analysis of Octane
- Successfully assisted in transitioning R&D products to commercial status (ISO: 9001:2008, 17025, 10012)

Additional Experience:

BP (British Petroleum) Research Associate March 2013 - October 2013

Ionis Pharmaceuticals (Formerly ISIS Pharmaceuticals) Research Associate/Scientist - Oligo Synthesis October 2012 - November 2012

The Scripps Research Institute Research Technician July 2006 - July 2011